mandela.ac.za 2018-10-21

# Privacy statement

##  PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT

The Nelson Mandela University (hereafter referred to as “the University”) respects the privacy of all users who visit in our websites or communicate electronically with us. The Privacy Policy therefore provides an explanation on how the University gathers and disseminate information for all University websites:

##  INFORMATION COLLECTED AUTOMATICALLY BY THE UNIVERSITY

Generally, you can visit our websites without explicitly telling us who you are or revealing any personal identifiable information about yourself. We do, however, record your IP address, browser type, pages visited and other such information. Log files are used to analyse website usage and may be kept in an aggregated and anonymised form for historical records. The broad demographic information gathered about our visitors help us assess our target audience, and to determine which external sites are most effective in referring visitors to us. This helps us to align our content to the needs of our audiences. The University does not share the collected information with any other organisation for commercial purposes.

##  INFORMATION COLLECTED MANUALLY BY THE UNIVERSITY

You may come across registration forms that require you to provide us with personal identifiable information (like your name, surname, email address, contact numbers, and postal or work address), and perhaps some additional information. The collected information may be shared within the University as a whole unless otherwise stipulated during the collection process. The collected information may be stored and processed outside your country (if outside South Africa) and by using the University’s websites, you consent to any such transfers being made outside your country.

##  USE OF INFORMATION COLLECTED BY THE UNIVERSITY

The information provided by you is used to get in contact with you in response to a query from you, to improve the University websites or, in case of a conference, to register you as a participant. No personal information submitted by you will be shared or made public without your prior consent or unless required to do so by law.

##  COOKIES

Some of our websites may use cookies to store any preferences you may have expressed. Cookies are like tokens for a specific web page that the web server stores on your computer. The next time you visit us, your computer will pass the cookie back to our server and thus keep track of your preferences. This will allow our websites to personalise your online experience. Your browser can be set to warn you whether a cookie should be accepted or declined. Alternatively, you may disable cookies altogether, in which case you may not be able to visit these specific pages.

Further information about cookies may be found at:[www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

##  SECURITY

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

##  EXTERNAL LINKS

Some websites contain links to other sites. The Nelson Mandela Metropolitan University is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. One you leave our websites, we cannot guarantee the protection and privacy of your personal identifiable information collected by these sites. These links are provided just as a convenience and do not imply endorsement by the Nelson Mandela Metropolitan University.

##  DATA PROTECTION

The University ensures that all personal data is held in accordance with the Protection of Personal Information Act 4 of 2013. Should you have any query regarding Protection of Personal Information Act 4 of 2013 issues, please contact the University Legal Office.

##  CONSENT

By using the University websites, you give consent to the data practices described in this Privacy Policy Statement.

##  CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT

The University reserves the right to amend the Privacy Policy Statement. Any changes made to the Privacy Policy Statement are posted on this page. The University encourages you to periodically review the Privacy Policy Statement to be informed of how the University manages the collected information.

##  DISCLAIMER

It is the policy of the Nelson Mandela Metropolitan University to abide by and follow any rule of common or statutory law. Page content posted by individuals, departments and student organisations to the Nelson Mandela Metropolitan University’s websites reflect their own opinions, interests, and activities; they do not implicitly or explicitly represent official policies or positions of the Nelson Mandela Metropolitan University. Individual content maintainers assume responsibility and liability for the content of their pages. The Nelson Mandela Metropolitan University does not aggressively review, censor or control the contents of these pages, nor does it assume responsibility for any links that you may follow from them. For further assistance, contact the [webmaster@mandela.ac.za](mailto:webmaster@mandela.ac.za).
